<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<Spells>
	<Spell>
		<ID>1</ID>
		<Name>A Day in the Life – Halfling</Name>
		<Level>5</Level>
		<Components>V/S/M</Components>
		<Range>Touch</Range>
		<AreaOfEffect>Creature Touched</AreaOfEffect>
		<Save>Neg.</Save>
		<CastingTime>8</CastingTime>
		<Duration>1 day</Duration>
		<Class>Priest</Class>
		<School>Alteration/Abjuration</School>
		<Book>Priest’s Spell Compendium Vol. 1</Book>
		<Description>This spell transforms a living, sentient, intelligent creature touched by the caster (successful attack roll required) into a normal halfling with no character class abilities (see the Monstrous Manual tome) provided the creature fails a saving throw vs. spell. The creature transformed retains its alignment, its memory and mental capacity, its normal saving throws, and its hit points. It does not gain the saving throw bonuses that halflings normally possess; the spell gives halfling form and THAC0. Items carried or worn are not changed with the creature, which may not be awash in ill-fitting armor or holding a weapon too big to wield effectively. Magical items usable only by character classes other than fighters no longer function for the creature. The casting of spells by a creature transformed by a day in the life is not possible, although they are not forgotten and can be cast when the creature once again assumes its normal form; similarly, the use of psionic capabilities granted by the psionicist class is not possible. The spell does not require  a system shock roll for the creature when it is transformed or when it assumes its normal form; at the spell’s expiration.
			The material components are the priest’s holy symbol and a hair from a halfling’s foot.
			NOTE: Granted by the halfling deity Yondalla.
		</Description>
	</Spell>
	<Spell>
		<ID>2</ID>
		<Name>Affect Normal Fires</Name>
		<Level>1</Level>
		<Components>V/S/M</Components>
		<Range>5 yds./level</Range>
		<AreaOfEffect>10 ft. radius</AreaOfEffect>
		<Save>None</Save>
		<CastingTime>1</CastingTime>
		<Duration>2 rds./level</Duration>
		<Class>Wizard</Class>
		<School>Alteration</School>
		<Book>Player's Handbook (Revised)</Book>
		<Description>This spell enables the wizard to cause nonmagical fires - from as small as a torch or lantern to as large as the area of effect - to reduce in size and brightness to become mere coals or increase in light ot become as bright as full daylight and increase the illumination to dobule the normal radius. Note that this does not affect either fuel consumption or damage caused by the fire. The caster can affect any or all fires in the spell's area. He can alter their intensities with a single gesture as long as the spell is in effect. The spell lasts until caster cancels it, all fuel is burned, or the duration expires. The caster can also extinguish all flames in the area, which expends the spell immediately. The spell does not affect fire elements or similar creatures.</Description>
	</Spell>
	<Spell>
		<ID>3</ID>
		<Name>Alarm</Name>
		<Level>1</Level>
		<Components>V/S/M</Components>
		<Range>10 yds.</Range>
		<AreaOfEffect>Up to 20 ft. cube</AreaOfEffect>
		<Save>None</Save>
		<CastingTime>1 rd.</CastingTime>
		<Duration>4 hrs. + 1/2hr./level</Duration>
		<Class>Wizard</Class>
		<School>Abjuration/Evocation</School>
		<Book>Player's Handbook (Revised)</Book>
		<Description>When an alarm spell is cast, the wizard causes a selected area to react to the presence of any creature larger than a normal rat - anything larger than about 1/2 cubic foot in volume or more than about three pounds in weight. The area of effect can be a portal, a section of floor, stairs, etc. As soon as any creature enters the warded area, touches it, or otherwise contacts it without speaking a password established by the caster, the alarm spell lets out a loud ringing that can be heard clearly within a 60ft. radius. (Reduce the radius by 10 feet for each interposing door  and by 20 feet for each substantial interposing wall.) The sound lasts for one round and then ceases. Ethereal or astrally projected creatures do not trigger an alarm, but flying or levitating creatures, invisible creatures, or incorporeal or gaseous creatures do. The caster can dismiss the alarm witha  single word.
		The material components of this spell are a tiny bell and a piece of very fine silver wire.</Description>
	</Spell>
	<Spell>
		<ID>4</ID>
		<Name>Armor</Name>
		<Level>1</Level>
		<Components>V/S/M</Components>
		<Range>Touch</Range>
		<AreaOfEffect>1 creature</AreaOfEffect>
		<Save>None</Save>
		<CastingTime>1 rd.</CastingTime>
		<Duration>Special</Duration>
		<Class>Wizard</Class>
		<School>Conjuration</School>
		<Book>Player's Handbook (Revised)</Book>
		<Description>By means of this spell, the wizard creates a magical field of force that serves as if it were scale mail armor (AC 6). The spell has no effect on a person already armored or a creature with Armor Class 6 or better. It is not cumulative with the shield spell, but it is cumulative with the Dexterity and, in case of fighter/mages, with the shield bonus. The armor spell does not hinder movement or prevent spellcasting, and adds no weight or encumbrance. It lasts until successfully dispelled or until the wearer sustains cumulative damage totaling greater than 8 points + 1 per level of the caster. (It is important to note that the armor does not absorb this damage. The armor merely grants an AC of 6; the wearer still suffers full damage from any successful attacks.) Thus, the wearer might suffer 8 points from an attack, then several minutes later sustain an additional 1 point of damage. Unless the spell were cast by a wizard of 2nd level or higher, it would be dispelled at this time. Until it is dispelled, the armor spell grants the wearer full benefits of the Armor Class gained.
		The material component is a piece of finely cured leather that has been blessed by a priest.</Description>
	</Spell>
	<Spell>
		<ID>5</ID>
		<Name>Audible Glamer</Name>
		<Level>1</Level>
		<Components>V/S/M</Components>
		<Range>60 yds. + 10 yds./level</Range>
		<AreaOfEffect>Hearing Range</AreaOfEffect>
		<Save>Special</Save>
		<CastingTime>1</CastingTime>
		<Duration>3 rds./level</Duration>
		<Class>Wizard</Class>
		<School>Illusion/Phantasm</School>
		<Book>Player's Handbook (Revised)</Book>
		<Description></Description>
	</Spell>
	<Spell>
		<ID>6</ID>
		<Name>Burning Hands</Name>
		<Level>1</Level>
		<Components>V/S</Components>
		<Range>0</Range>
		<AreaOfEffect>The Caster</AreaOfEffect>
		<Save>1/2</Save>
		<CastingTime>1</CastingTime>
		<Duration>Instantaneous</Duration>
		<Class>Wizard</Class>
		<School>Alteration</School>
		<Book>Player's Handbook (Revised)</Book>
		<Description>When the wizard casts this spell, a jet of searing flame shoots from his fingertips. His hands must be held so as to send forth a fanlike sheet of flames: The wizard's thumbs must touch each other and the fingers must be spread. The burning hands send out flame jets 5 feet long in a horizontal arc of about 120 degrees in front of the wizard. Any creature in the area of the flames fuffers 1d3 points of damage, plus 2 points for each level of experience of the spellcaster, to a maximum of 1d3+20 points of fire damage. Those successfully saving vs. spell receive half damage. Flammable materials touched by the fire burn (for example, cloth paper, parchment, thin wodd, ect.) Such materials can be extinguished in the next round if no other action is taken.</Description>
	</Spell>
	<Spell>
		<ID>7</ID>
		<Name>Cantrip</Name>
		<Level>1</Level>
		<Components>V/S</Components>
		<Range>10 ft.</Range>
		<AreaOfEffect>Special</AreaOfEffect>
		<Save>None</Save>
		<CastingTime>1</CastingTime>
		<Duration>1 hr./level</Duration>
		<Class>Wizard</Class>
		<School>Alteration(All schools) Fix Later</School>
		<Book>Player's Handbook (Revised)</Book>
		<Description>Cantrips are minor spells studied by wizards during their apprenticeship, regardless of school. The cantrip spell is a practice method for the apprentice, teaching him how to tap minute amounts of magical energy. Once cast, the cantrip spell enables the caster to create minor magical effects for the duration of the spell. However, these effects are so minor that they have severe limitations. They are completely unable to cause a loss of hit points, cannot affect the concentratin of spellcasters, and can only create small obviously magical materials. Furthermore, materials created by a cantrip are extremely fragile and cannot be used as tools of any sort. Lastly, a cantrip lacks the power to duplicate an other spell effects.
                 Whatever manifestation the cantrip takes, it remains in effect only as long as the wizard concentrates. Wizards typically use cantrips to limpress common folk, amuse children, and brighten dreary lives. Common tricks with cantrips include tinklings of ethereal music, brightening faded flowers, glowing balls that float over the caster's hand, puffs of wind to flicker candles, spicing up aromas and flavors of bland food, and little whirlwinds to sweed dust under rugs. Combined with the unseen servant spell, it's a tool to make housekeeping and entertaining simpler for the wizard.</Description>
	</Spell>
        <Spell>
		<ID>8</ID>
		<Name>Change Self</Name>
		<Level>1</Level>
		<Components>V/S</Components>
		<Range>0</Range>
		<AreaOfEffect>The Caster</AreaOfEffect>
		<Save>None</Save>
		<CastingTime>1</CastingTime>
		<Duration>2d6 rds. + 2 rds./level</Duration>
		<Class>Wizard</Class>
		<School>Illusion/Phantasm</School>
		<Book>Player's Handbook (Revised)</Book>
		<Description>This spell enables the wizard to alter the appearance of his form--including clothing and equipment--to appear 1 foot shorter or taller; thin, fat, or in between; human, humanoid, or any other generally man-shaped bipedal creature. The caster cannot duplicate a specific individual. The spell does not provide the abilities or mannerisms of the chosen form. The duration of the spell is 2d6 rounds plus two additional rounds per level of experience of the spellcaster. The DM may allow a saving throw for disbelief under certain circumstances: for example, if the caster acts in a manner obviously inconsistent with his chosen role. The spell does not alter the perceived tactile (i.e. touch) properties of the caster or his equipment, and the ruse can be discovered in this way.</Description>
	</Spell>
        <Spell>
		<ID>9</ID>
		<Name>Charm Person</Name>
		<Level>1</Level>
		<Components>V/S</Components>
		<Range>120 yds.</Range>
		<AreaOfEffect>1 person</AreaOfEffect>
		<Save>Neg.</Save>
		<CastingTime>1</CastingTime>
		<Duration>Special</Duration>
		<Class>Wizard</Class>
		<School>Enchantment/Charm</School>
		<Book>Player's Handbook (Revised)</Book>
		<Description>This spell affects any single person it is cast upon. The term person includes any bipedal human, demihuman or humanoid of man size or smaller, such as brownies, dryads, dwarves, elves, gnolls, gnomes, goblins, half-elves, halflings, half-orcs, hobgoblins, humans, kobolds, lizard men, nixies, orcs, pixies sprites, troglodytes, and others. Thus a 10th-level fighter could be charmed, but and ogre could not.
                The person receives a saving throw vs. spell to avoid the effect, with an adjustments due to Wisdom (see Table 5). If the person receives damage from the caster's group in the same round the charm is cast, an additional bonus of +1 per hit point of damage received is added to the victim's saving throw.
                If the spell recipient fails his saving throw, he regards the caster as a trusted friend and ally to be heeded and protected. The spell does not enable the caster to control the charmed creature as if it were an automaton, but any word or action of the caster is viewed in the most favorable way. Thus a charmed person would not obey a suicide command, but he might believe the caster if assured that the only chance to save the caster's life is for the person ot hold back an onrushing red dragon for "just a minute or two." Note also that the spell does not endow the caster with linguistic capabilities beyond those lhe normally possesses (i.e., he must speak the victim's language to communicate his commands).
                The duration of the spell is a function of the charmed person's Intelligence and is tied ot the saving throw. The spell may be broken if a successful saving throw is rolled, and this saving throw is checked on a periodic basis, according ot the creatures' Intelligence (see the following table). If the caster harms, or attempts to harm, the charmed person by some overt action, or is a dispel magic spell is successfully cast updon the charmed person, the charm spell is broken.
                If two or more charm effects simultaneously effect a creature, the result is decided by the DM. This could range from one effect being clearly dominant, to the subject being town by conflicting desires, to new saving throws that could negate both spells.
                Note that the subject has full memory of the events that took place while he was charmed.
                (TABLE)
                NOTE: The period between checks is the time period during which the check occurs. When to roll the check during this time is determined (randomly or by selection) by the DM. The roll is made secretly.</Description>
	</Spell>
        <Spell>
		<ID>10</ID>
		<Name>Chill Touch</Name>
		<Level>1</Level>
		<Components>V/S</Components>
		<Range>0</Range>
		<AreaOfEffect>The  Caster</AreaOfEffect>
		<Save>Neg.</Save>
		<CastingTime>1</CastingTime>
		<Duration>3 rds. + 1 rd./level</Duration>
		<Class>Wizard</Class>
		<School>Necromancy</School>
		<Book>Player's Handbook (Revised)</Book>
		<Description>When  the  caster  completes  this  spell,  a  blue  glow  encompasses his  hand.  This  energy  attacks  the  life  force  of  any  living  creature upon  which  the  wizard  makes  a  successful  melee  attack.  The touched  creature  must  roll  a  successful  saving  throw  vs.  spell  or  suf­ fer  1d4  points  of damage  and  lose  I  point  of  Strength.  If  the  save  is successful,  the  creature  remains  unharmed.  Creatures  not  rated  for Strength  suffer  a  -1  penalty  to  their  attack  rolls  for  every  other  suc­ cessful  touch.  Lost  Strength  returns  at  the  rate  of  1  point  per  hour. Damage  must  be  cured  magically  or  healed  naturally. 
This  spell  has  a  special  effect  on  undead  creatures.  Undead touched  by  the  caster  suffer  no  damage  or  Strength  loss,  but  they must  successfully  save  vs.  spell  or  flee  for  1d4  rounds  +  1  round per  level  of  the  caster.</Description>
	</Spell>
        <Spell>
		<ID>11</ID>
		<Name>Color Spray</Name>
		<Level>1</Level>
		<Components>V/S/M</Components>
		<Range>0</Range>
		<AreaOfEffect>5x20x20 ft. wedge</AreaOfEffect>
		<Save>Special</Save>
		<CastingTime>1</CastingTime>
		<Duration>Instantaneous</Duration>
		<Class>Wizard</Class>
		<School>Alteration</School>
		<Book>Player's Handbook (Revised)</Book>
		<Description>Upon  casting  this  spell,  the  wizard  causes  a  vivid,  fan-shaped spray  of  clashing  colors  to  spring  forth  from  his  hand.  From  one  to six  creatures  (Id6)  within  the  area  are  affected  in  order  of  increas­ ing  distance  from  the  wizard.  All  creatures  above  the  level  of  the spellcaster  and  all  those  of  6th  level  or  6  Hit  Dice  or  more  are  enti­ tled  to  a  saving  throw  vs.  spell.  Blind  or  unseeing  creatures  are  not affected  by  the  spell. 
Creatures  not  allowed  or  failing  saving  throws,  and  whose  Hit Dice  or  levels  are  less  than  or  equal  to  the  spellcaster's  level,  are struck  unconscious  for  2d4  rounds;  those  with  Hit  Dice  or  levels  I or  2  greater  than  the  wizard's  level  are  blinded  for  1d4  rounds; those  with  Hit  Dice  or  levels  3  or  more  greater  than  that  of  the  spell­ caster  are  stunned  (reeling  and  unable  to  think  or  act  coherently)  for one  round. 
The  material  components  of  this  spell  are  a  pinch  each  of  pow­ der  or  sand  that  is  colored  red,  yellow,  and  blue. </Description>
	</Spell>
        <Spell>
		<ID>12</ID>
		<Name>Comprehend  Languages</Name>
		<Level>1</Level>
		<Components>V/S/M</Components>
		<Range>Touch</Range>
		<AreaOfEffect>1 speaking creature or written text</AreaOfEffect>
		<Save>None</Save>
		<CastingTime>1 rd.</CastingTime>
		<Duration>5 rds./level</Duration>
		<Class>Wizard</Class>
		<School>Alteration</School>
		<Book>Player's Handbook (Revised)</Book>
		<Description>When  this  spell  is  cast,  the  wizard  is  able  to  understand  the  spo­ ken  words  of  a  creature  or  read  an  otherwise  incomprehensible  writ­ 
ten  message  (such  as  writing  in  another  language).  In  either  case, the  wizard  must  touch  the  creature  or  the  writing.  Note  that  the  abill­ ity  to  read  does  not  necessarily  impart  understanding  of  the  mater­ ial,  nor  does  the  spell  enable  the  caster  to  speak  or  write  an unknown  language.  Written  material  can  be  read  at  the  rate  of  one page  or  equivalent  per  round.  Magical  writing  cannot  be  read,  other than  to  know  it  is  magical,  but  the  spell  is  often  useful  when  deci­ phering  treasure  maps.  This  spell  can  be  foiled  by  certain  warding magic  (the  3rd-level  secret  page  and  illusionary  script  spells),  and  it 
does  not  reveal  messages  concealed  in  otherwise  normal  text. The  material  components  of  this  spell  are  a  pinch  of  soot  and  a few  grains  of  salt.
The  reverse  of  this  spell,  confuse  languages,  cancels  a  compre­ hend  languages  spell  or  renders  a writing  or  a  creature's  speech incomprehensible,  for  the  same  duration  as  above. </Description>
	</Spell>
        <Spell>
		<ID>13</ID>
		<Name>Dancing Lights</Name>
		<Level>1</Level>
		<Components>V/S/M</Components>
		<Range>40  yds.  +  10  yds./level</Range>
		<AreaOfEffect>Special</AreaOfEffect>
		<Save>None</Save>
		<CastingTime>1</CastingTime>
		<Duration>2  rds./level</Duration>
		<Class>Wizard</Class>
		<School>Alteration</School>
		<Book>Player's Handbook (Revised)</Book>
		<Description>When  a  dancing  lights  spell  is  cast,  the  wizard  creates,  at  his option,  from  one  to  four  lights  that  resemble  either  torches  or lanterns  (and  cast  that  amount  of  light),  glowing  spheres  of  light (such  as  evidenced  by  will-o-wisps),  or  one  faintly  glowing,  vaguely manlike  shape,  somewhat  similar  to  that  of  a  creature  from  the  Ele­ mental  Plane  of  Fire.  The  dancing  lights  move  as  the  spellcaster desires,  forward  or  back,  straight  or  turning  corners,  without  concen­ tration  upon  such  movement  by  the  wizard.  The  spell  cannot  be used  to  cause  blindness  (see  the  1st-level  light  spell),  and  it  winks out  if  the  range  or  duration  is  exceeded. 
The  material  component  of  this  spell  is  either  a  bit  of  phospho­ rus  or  wychwood,  or  a  glowworm. </Description>
	</Spell>
        <Spell>
		<ID>14</ID>
		<Name>Detect Magic</Name>
		<Level>1</Level>
		<Components>V/S</Components>
		<Range>0</Range>
		<AreaOfEffect>10  x 60  ft</AreaOfEffect>
		<Save>None</Save>
		<CastingTime>1</CastingTime>
		<Duration>2  rds./level</Duration>
		<Class>Wizard</Class>
		<School>Divination</School>
		<Book>Player's Handbook (Revised)</Book>
		<Description>When  the  detect  magic  spell  is  cast,  the  wizard  detects  magical radiations  in  a  path  10 feet  wide  and  up  to  60  feet  long  in  the  direc­ tion  he  is  facing.  The  intensity  of  the  magic  can  be  determined  (dim, faint,  moderate,  strong,  overwhelming),  and  the  wizard  has  a  100% chance  per  level  to  recognize  if  a  certain  type  of  magic  (alteration, conjuration,  etc.)  is  present.  The  caster  can  turn,  scanning  a  60­ degree  arc  per  round.  A  stone  wall  of  1  foot  or  more  thickness,  solid metal  of  1  inch  thickness,  or  a  yard  or  more  of  solid  wood  blocks  the spell.  Magical  areas,  multiple  types  of  magic,  or  strong  local  magical emanations  may  confuse  or  conceal  weaker  radiations.  Note  that this  spell  does  not  reveal  the  presence  of  good  or  evil,  or  reveal alignment.  Otherplanar  creatures  are  not  necessarily  magical. </Description>
	</Spell>

</Spells>